# Juan Orozco



919-793-3740

<u>JuanOrozco.com</u>

JuanTheDesigner@gmail.com

# **Personal Summary**

My wonder and zeal for inventing and exploring is at the core of my many passions. As a designer and wannabe engineer, I focused on Industrial Design. I also have a passion for writing, photography, and anthropology. Finding a world ripe with new exploration opportunities, I pivoted and turned to the web. I dove in with the aim of learning as much as possible in order to express all of my passions.

Through my diverse work experiences over the past ten years, I have honed my skills as a web developer; first as a server-side craftsman. I then moved on to front-end development and User Experience. Currently, I am focused on publishing and mentoring. Through the web I publish thoughts on creativity, web engineering, and gaming. I attend several local Meetups to learn and to mentor.

The web is still in a formative state, which encourages exploration and community. Within this dynamic, I continue to learn and participate in all aspects of web application development, self publishing through the web, and the sharing of knowledge.

# **Objective**

I am at my best when creating innovative, inspiring, challenging, and fun solutions within a respectful and creative company, alongside talented and friendly team members.

### **Skills**

#### Languages, Data Formats

CoffeeScript	CSS	4D	GIT
HTML	JavaScript	JSON	Lua
Markdown	MSSQL	MySQL	Node.js
Pascal (Delphi)	PHP	Ruby	SVN
XML	1	-	1

#### Frameworks

CANJS	DHTMLx	jQuery	jQuery UI
Mustache	PHPUnit	Pure CSS	qUnit
RequireIS	Selenium	Underscore	'

#### **Services & APIs**

Bamboo	Bower	Confluence	Dropbox
Evernote	Firebase	FishEye	Grunt
Gulp	Jira	Mozilla Persona	OAuth
Trello	WordPress	Yeoman	1

## **Experience**

#### **Application Engineer at Knowledge Sharing Systems**

Raleigh, NC; Nov. 2012 - Current

#### PHP, 4D, Node.js, Selenium, PHPUnit, HTML, CSS, JavaScript

- Introduced versioning using Subversion and GIT.
- Spearheaded automated builds and integration testing with Selenium and PHPUnit using Bamboo.
- Improved core application MVC structure by creating a basic API and a more scalable MVC structure.
- Learned the 4D scripting language and API.
- General application engineering creating and modifying modules for the flagship application and SaaS applications.
- Conducted research with end users.
- User Experience work included user research and interface design.

#### **Lead Web Developer at Maximum Processing**

Garner, NC; Jun. 2011 - Nov. 2012

#### Pascal/Delphi, MSSQL, HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, Selenium

- Lead project developer for multiple clients; managed milestones and issue tracking.
- Designed and built various portable and dynamic modules for core system that reduced developer time and bug tickets.
- Initiated and increased awareness of development best practices through training, company Wiki, and Code Snippet repository.
- Moved code base from in-house versioning system to more robust Subversion.

#### Web Developer at City of Fayetteville

Fayetteville, NC; Jan. 2011 - Jun. 2011

#### ASP.NET, VB.NET, HTML, CSS, JavaScript/jQuery

- Project lead on internal application for city employees that built dynamic forms.
- Responsible for websites including main landing site, the Police Department, and the Fire Department.
- Built custom responsive CSS and JavaScript frameworks for use on all city owned websites.
- Designed and implemented various interfaces for geographic data using GIS data and Google Maps API.
- User experience advising and mentoring with application developers and GIS developers.
- Utilized ADA-compliance and accessibility techniques.

#### **Application and Experience Engineer at End Game Studio**

Raleigh, NC; Jul. 2005 - Current

#### Front end technologies, Bower and Grunt for automation and builds, PHP and WordPress for backend and CMS.

- Full stack developer for private and commercial clients.
- UX Engineer User research, interface designer, copy editor.
- Maintain web host server and WordPress CMS.
- Developed small web applications and tools to increase personal productivity and work-flow.

• Training on CMS, social media, and other tools

#### Technology Support Technician at College of Management, NCSU

Raleigh, NC; Oct. 2007 - Oct. 2008

- Supported classroom technology, student and faculty computing, and special event administration.
- Coordinated technology resources for lectures and presentations given by CEO's and other VIP's in 1500 seat auditorium.
- Deployed, supported, and repaired all faculty and student computing resources. Supervised volunteer students.
- Created documentation, scheduled training and recording sessions for video recording classroom.
- Consulted on design for upgrades and modification for instructional technology.
- Learned the Crestron Simple+ programming language; refactored and improved interfaces college-wide.

### **Education**

#### **Continuing Education**

Raleigh, NC, Winter/Sprint 2014

Various coursework on User Experience.

- User Experience Coursework on Udemy completed April 2014
- User Experience Class on Udacity completed April 2014

#### **ITT Technical Institute**

Oxnard, CA, Fall 2004

Electronics Technology, Programming

#### Ventura College

Ventura, CA, Fall 1999 - Summer 2004

Electrical Engineering, Architectural Drafting, Programming